At his call, Pythagoras as a 20-year-old went to Egypt to study, among other things, mathematics.
Among the lessons of the trip are what we today feel like Pythagora's kit - A2 B2 C2.
But Pythago's thinking went beyond that.
Like the other natural philosophers, Pythagoras were busy with the idea of finding everything's origin, a matter.
Where Thales said that everything's origin is water, Pythagoras meant that everything is speech.
He meant that the universe is made up of integers and that nothing can exist without a number.
Everything is speech, and the key to understanding them goes through mathematics.
The starting shot for Pythagora's philosophy is believed to have been his discovery of mathematical relationships in music
- that some sound frequencies are in nature harmonizing better than others.
He meant that because the relationship between tones can be expressed as speech and speech conditions
It should also be possible to describe everything else in the world in this way.
In order to explore the relationship of mathematics to reality, he founded a philosophical-religious school
which he uncommonly named after himself - Pythagoreans.
These studied mathematics and numerology, and their goal was to be able to say something about our world through abstract thinking.
This was the first time math is used for more than practical count
- Something that had a huge importance for future science.
As a pythagoré, one would indulge in philosophy.
In order to be accepted as one of Pythagora's disciples, one underwent an intake test
Which was about not having to say a word for five years.
You only had to listen to what the full pythagores had to say.
Then one would follow strict living rules to focus on mathematics.
Among other things, it was never possible to pick up a dropped object, touching white chickens,
stir in the fire with iron objects, speak in darkness, raise animals with crooked chlorine,
Break bread, step over the fence, pick flower bouquets or hike along a country road.
These rules were a way for the Pythagoreans to maintain and demonstrate self -control.
They lived together and had no personal possessions.
Among the more philosophically influenced rules, strict vegetarianism applied.
This when Pythagoras believed in self -hike and meant that one could be reborn like any animal.
Eating animals was therefore the same as eating people.
But most important of all was to avoid beans.
He had calculated that it is 216 years between each reincarnation,
and in between, our soul had to be stored somewhere
- And beans were nothing but containers for dormant souls.
Pythagoras was also the first with the idea that the earth was round and revolved around the sun,
The universe spherical and the planets of the planets circular.
This idea meant that one could now start calculating and predicting the movements and positions of the celestial bodies.
That people in the Middle Ages would believe that the earth was flat is a so -called factoid -
A performance held for true but which is in fact incorrect.
Already a few hundred years after Pythagoras, another Greek philosopher, Eratosthenes, the earth's circumference to 46,620 \ hkm.
Today we know that the circumference of the earth is 40,075 km
So it was certainly not a bad calculation given that it was over 2000 years ago.
When Nicolaus Copernicus in 1543 describes the heliocentric worldview (that the sun is at the center)
He himself calls the theory "Astronomia Pythagorica" as a tribute to Pythagora's theory that has now finally been proven.
For outsiders probably appeared the activities of the Pythagores as something very peculiar
and was considered with great suspicion.
According to the myth, Pythagoras came to be feared by the local population
which eventually came to rebelling when they feared he was engaged in black art.
Pythagoras must have moved for his life, chased, after which he reached a large prayer field.
Instead of trampling on the sacred beans, he must have stopped and awaited the persecutors and death.
In fact, we still have a reference to Pythagoras "Black Art" in popular culture
- Namely the pentagram or the "devil mark".